Let's do a quick example of the game, ship, captain, and crew, and then, for the rest of this series, we'll work on it in detail.
In a turn of ship, captain, and crew, you get three rolls, and you're trying to build first a ship, then have a captain assigned to it, and then collect a crew and then cargo.
Well, the ship equals number six.
On my first roll, I have no sixes.
So, I have to roll again.
Aha, there I rolled a six, so I have my ship.
Alas, there are no fives, no captain.
And, I only get one more roll, so let's hope this goes better.
Well, there's a five, so there is my captain and a die with four on it, equals the crew, and then once you have that, once you have ship, which is six, captain which is five, and crew which is four, you can use the remaining dice for your cargo.
In this case, it's a five and a three, and so now, I would score my points.
And, it's six plus five, which is eleven, plus four which is fifteen, plus eight more, twenty-three.
And there you have it.
That's ship, captain, and crew.
We'll go into detail in this series.